I'm going to start with a little story.
سوف ابدأ بقصة صغيرة
So, I grew up in this neighborhood. When I was 15 years old,
نشأت في هذه اﻷنحاء. و عندما بلغت الخامسة عشرة
I went from being what I think was a strapping young athlete,
و تحولت من ما كنت أظنه شاب رياضي مفتول العضلات
over four months, slowly wasting away until
خلال أربعة أشهر، ببطء بدأت أفقد الوزن
I was basically a famine victim
أصبحت ببساطة ضحية مجاعة
with an unquenchable thirst.
مع عطش لا يقارن
I had basically digested away my body.
ببساطة هضمت جسمي
And this all came to a head when I was on a backpacking trip,
وكل ذلك حين كنت في رحلة بحقيبة ظهر،
my first one ever actually, on Old Rag Mountain
أول رحلة لي في الحقيقة، على جبل أولد راج
in West Virginia, and was putting my face into puddles
في ويست فيرجينيا، وكنت أضع وجهي في برك
of water and drinking like a dog.
الماء و أشرب مثل الكلب.
That night, I was taken into the emergency room
في تلك الليلة، تم نقلي إلى غرفة الطوارئ
and diagnosed as a type 1 diabetic in full-blown ketoacidosis.
و تشخيصي بمرض السكري من النوع الأول في حماض كيتوني كامل.
And I recovered, thanks to the miracles of modern medicine,
و تعافيت، والشكر لأعجوبة الطب الحديث،
insulin and other things, and gained all my weight back and more.
الإنسولين و أشياء أخرى، و استعدت كامل وزني و زيادة.
And something festered inside me after this happened.
وشيء ما بداخلي تقرح بعد ما حدث ذلك.
What I thought about was, what caused the diabetes?
ما فكرت به، هو ما الذي سبّب السكري؟
You see, diabetes is an autoimmune disease
كما ترون، السكري مرض مناعة ذاتية
where your body fights itself, and at the time people thought
حيث يحارب جسمك نفسه، وفي ذلك الوقت الناس اعتقدوا
that somehow maybe exposure to a pathogen
أنه بطريقة ما ربما بسبب مرض معدي
had triggered my immune system to fight the pathogen
أثار نظامي المناعة في جسمي لمحاربة العدوى
and then kill the cells that make insulin.
ثم قتل الخلايا التي تصنع الأنسولين.
And this is what I thought for a long period of time,
وهذا ما اعتقدت لمدة طويلة،
and that's in fact what medicine and people have focused on quite a bit,
وفي الحقيقة ذلك ما ركز عليه الناس والطب لمدة من الزمن،
the microbes that do bad things.
أن الميكروبات تفعل أشياء سيئة.
And that's where I need my assistant here now.
واﻵن أحتاج مساعدتي هنا.
You may recognize her.
ربما تعرفونها.
So, I went yesterday, I apologize, I skipped a few of the talks,
لذا، ذهبت بالأمس، أعتذر، تغيبت عن بعض الأحاديث هنا،
and I went over to the National Academy of Sciences building,
وذهبت إلى مبنى الأكاديمية القومية للعلوم،
and they sell toys, giant microbes.
وهم يبيعون الألعاب، ميكروبات عملاقة.
And here we go!
هيا بنا!
So you have caught flesh-eating disease if you caught that one.
سوف تصاب بمرض آكل-اللحم إذا أمسكت هذه
I gotta get back out my baseball ability here.
يجب أن أستعيد قدراتي في البيسبول هنا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So, unfortunately or not surprisingly, most of the microbes
لذا، لسوء الحظ أو بدون مفاجأة، معظم الميكروبات،
they sell at the National Academy building are pathogens.
التي يبيعون في مبنى الأكاديمية القومية للعلوم مسببة للمرض.
Everybody focuses on the things that kill us,
الجميع يركز على الأشياء التي تقتلنا،
and that's what I was focusing on.
وذلك ما كنت أركز عليه.
And it turns out that we are covered in a cloud of microbes,
واتضح أننا مغطوّن في سحابة من الميكروبات،
and those microbes actually do us good much of the time,
وتلك المكروبات فعلياً تفعل لنا الخير في الكثير من الوقت،
rather than killing us.
بدلاً من قتلنا.
And so, we've known about this for some period of time.
ولقد، عرفنا هذا لمدة من الزمن.
People have used microscopes to look at the microbes that cover us,
الناس استخدموا المجاهر لمراقبة الميكروبات التي تغطينا،
I know you're not paying attention to me, but ...
أعلم أنكم لا تعيروني الانتباه، لكن ...
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
The microbes that cover us.
الميكروبات التي تغطينا.
And if you look at them in the microscope,
لو نظرت إليها بالمجهر،
you can see that we actually have 10 times as many cells
تستطيع أن ترى أننا نملك عشرة أضعاف
of microbes on us as we have human cells.
عدد خلايانا البشرية من الميكروبات علينا.
There's more mass in the microbes than the mass of our brain.
كتلة الميكروبات أكبر من كتلة دماغنا.
We are literally a teeming ecosystem of microorganisms.
نحن حرفيا نظام إيكولوجي زاخر بالكائنات الدقيقة.
And unfortunately, if you want to learn about the microorganisms,
ولسوء الحظ، إذا أردت أن تتعلم عن الكائنات الدقيقة،
just looking at them in a microscope is not sufficient.
النظر إليها بالمجهر فقط لا يكفي.
And so we just heard about the DNA sequencing.
ولقد سمعنا مؤخرا عن تسلسل الدي-إن-أي
It turns out that one of the best ways to look at microbes
اتضح أن ذلك من أفضل الطرق للنظر إلى الميكروبات
and to understand them is to look at their DNA.
لفهمها يجب البحث في الدي-إن-أي الخاص بها.
And that's what I've been doing for 20 years,
وذلك ما كنت أفعله منذ 20 سنة،
using DNA sequencing, collecting samples from various places,
باستخدام تسلسل الدي-إن-أي، وجمع العينات من أماكن مختلفة،
including the human body, reading the DNA sequence
متضمنا جسم الإنسان، بقراءة تسلسل الدي-إن-أي
and then using that DNA sequencing to tell us about
ثم باستخدام سلاسل الدي-إن-أي تلك لتخبرنا عن
the microbes that are in a particular place.
الميكروبات الموجودة في مكان معين.
And what's amazing, when you use this technology,
والرائع، عندما تستخدم تلك التقنية،
for example, looking at humans, we're not just covered
على سبيل المثال، بالنظر إلى البشر، نحن لسنا فقط مغطيّن
in a sea of microbes.
في بحر من الميكروبات.
There are thousands upon thousands of different kinds of microbes on us.
يوجد آلاف الآلاف من أنواع من الميكروبات علينا.
We have millions of genes of microbes in our human
لدينا ملايين الجينات من الميكروبات في
microbiome covering us.
ميكروبيوم من جسمنا تغطينا.
And so this microbial diversity differs between people,
وهذا التعدد الميكروبي يختلف بين الناس،
and what people have been thinking about in the last 10,
وما كان يفكر فيه الناس في العشر سنين السابقة،
maybe 15 years is, maybe these microbes,
ربما 15 سنة، أنه ربما هذه الميكروبات،
this microbial cloud in and on us,
هذه السحابة الميكروبية داخلنا وعلينا،
and the variation between us, may be responsible
والإختلاف بيننا، ربما هو مسؤول
for some of the health and illness differences between us.
عن بعض الإختلافات الصحية و المرضية بيننا.
And that comes back to the diabetes story I was telling you.
وذلك يعود لقصة المرض السكري التي كنت أخبركم بها.
It turns out that people now think that one of the triggers
إتضّح أن الناس الآن يعتقدون أن واحد من المثيرات
for type 1 diabetes is not fighting a pathogen,
للنوع الأول من السكري هو ليس محاربة العامل الممرض،
but is in fact trying to -- miscommunicating with the microbes
لكن في الحقيقة هو محاولة -- خاطئة للاتصال بالميكروبات
that live in and on you.
التي تعيش داخلنا وعلينا.
And somehow maybe the microbial community that's
وبطريقة ما ربما المجتمع الميكروبي الذي
in and on me got off, and then this triggered some sort
علينا وداخلنا اشتعل، وذلك أثار نوع من
of immune response and led to me killing the cells
ردة الفعل مناعية أدت إلى قتل الخلايا
that make insulin in my body.
التي تصنع الأنسولين في جسمي.
And so what I want to tell you about for a few minutes is,
ولذا ما أريد أن أخبركم عنه في الدقائق القليلة القادمة هو،
what people have learned using DNA sequencing techniques
ماذا تعلم الناس من تقنيات سلاسل الدي-إن-أي
in particular, to study the microbial cloud
بالتحديد، لدراسة السحابة الميركروبية
that lives in and on us.
التي تعيش علينا وداخلنا.
And I want to tell you a story about a personal project.
و أريد ان أخبركم قصة عن مشروع خاص.
My first personal experience with studying the microbes
أول تجربة شخصية مع دراسة الميكروبات
on the human body actually came from a talk that I gave,
التي على الجسم البشري جاءت من حديث أعطيته،
right around the corner from here at Georgetown.
بالقرب من هنا في الزاوية في جورج تاون.
I gave a talk, and a family friend who happened to be
أعطيت حديث، وصديق للعائلة حدث أن كان
the Dean of Georgetown Medical School was at the talk,
عمدة لمدرسة الطب في جورجي تاون كان متواجداً في الحديث،
and came up to me afterwards saying, they were doing
وجاء إلي فيما بعد قائلاً، أنهم
a study of ileal transplants in people.
يعملون دراسة عن الزراعة اللفائفية في الناس.
And they wanted to look at the microbes after the transplants.
و أرادوا أن ينظروا إلى الميكروبات بعد الزراعات.
And so I started a collaboration with this person,
وبدأت في التعاون مع هذا الشخص،
Michael Zasloff and Thomas Fishbein, to look at the microbes
مايكل زاسلوف و توماس فيشباين، للبحث في الميكروبات
that colonized these ilea after they were transplanted into a recipient.
التي تستعمر اللفائف بعد ماتم زراعتها في المستقبل.
And I can tell you all the details about the microbial study
وأستطيع أن أخبركم عن كل التفاصيل المتعلقة بالدراسة المتعلقة بالميكروبات
that we did there, but the reason I want to tell you this story
التي عملناها هناك، لكن السبب الذي دفعني أن أقصّ عليكم هذه القصة
is something really striking that they did at the beginning
هو شيء جداً مدهش فعلوه في بداية
of this project.
هذا المشروع.
They take the donor ileum, which is filled with microbes from a donor
أخذوا من المتبرع الدقاق (جزء بسيط من الأمعاء اللفائفية)،
and they have a recipient who might have a problem
و من جهة المستقبل الذي قد يواجه مشكلة ما في
with their microbial community, say Crohn's disease,
مجتمعه الميكروبي، افترض مثلاً مرض كرون،
and they sterilized the donor ileum.
ويعقمون دقاق المتبرع.
Cleaned out all the microbes, and then put it in the recipient.
ينظفون كل الميكروبات، ثم يضعونها في المُستقبِل.
They did this because this was common practice
كانوا يفعلون ذلك لأنك كإجراء عام
in medicine, even though it was obvious
في الطب، بالرغم من أنه كان من الواضح
that this was not a good idea.
أنه ليس فكرة جيدة.
And fortunately, in the course of this project,
ولحسن الحظ، خلال مسار هذا المشروع،
the transplant surgeons and the other people
جراحين الزراعة و أشخاص آخرون
decided, forget common practice. We have to switch.
قرروا، أن ينسوا الإجراءات العامة. يجب أن نبدل.
So they actually switched to leaving some of the microbial
لذا بدلوا فعلياً إلى ترك بعض من
community in the ileum. They leave the microbes with the donor,
المجتمع الميكروبي في الأمعاء اللفائفية. تركوا الميكروبات في المتبرع
and theoretically that might help the people who are
ونظرياً ذلك قد يساعد الأشخاص الذين
receiving this ileal transplant.
يستقبلون زراعة المعو اللفائفي.
And so, people -- this is a study that I did now.
ولذلك، الأشخاص -- هذه دراسة عملتها الآن.
In the last few years there's been a great expansion
في السنوات القليلة كان هناك توسع كبير.
in using DNA technology to study the microbes in and on people.
في استخدام تقنية الدي إن إي لدراسة الميكروبات في داخل و على الإنسان.
There's something called the Human Microbiome Project
يوجد شيء يسمى مشروع الميكروبيوم البشري،
that's going on in the United States,
الذي يجري في الولايات المتحدة،
and MetaHIT going on in Europe, and a lot of other projects.
و MetaHIT تجري في أوروبا، و العديد من المشاريع الأخرى.
And when people have done a variety of studies,
وعندما يجري الناس العديد من التجارب،
they have learned things such as, when a baby is
يتعلمون أشياء مثل، عندما الجنين
born, during vaginal delivery you get colonized by the
يولد، خلال الولادة المهبلية يتم استعمارك عن طريق
microbes from your mother.
ميكروبات من أمك.
There are risk factors associated with cesarean sections,
يوجد عناصر خطورة مرتبطة مع العمليات القيصرية،
some of those risk factors may be due to mis-colonization
بعض هذه العناصر ترتبط بسوء استعمار عندما تشرح الطفل لتخرجه من والدته
when you carve a baby out of its mother
عندما يخرج الطفل بعملية
rather than being delivered through the birth canal.
بدلاً من ولادته خلال قناة الولادة.
And a variety of other studies have shown that the
و العديد من الدراسات الأخرى أظهرت أن
microbial community that lives in and on us
المجتمع الميكروبي الذي يعيش علينا وداخلنا
helps in development of the immune system,
يساعد في تطوير نظامنا المناعي،
helps in fighting off pathogens, helps in our metabolism,
يساعد في محاربة مسببات المرض، يساعد في الأيض
and determining our metabolic rate, probably
ويحدد معدل الأيض،
determines our odor, and may even shape our behavior
ربما يحدد رائحتنا، وربما يشكل سلوكياتنا
in a variety of ways.
بطرق متعددة.
And so, these studies have documented or suggested
ولذلك، هذه الدراسات وثقت أو اقترحت
out of a variety of important functions for the microbial community,
العديد من الوظائف المهمة للمجتمع الميكروبي،
this cloud, the non-pathogens that live in and on us.
هذه السحابة، اللامسببة للأمراض، التي تعيش علينا و داخلنا.
And one area that I think is very interesting,
و منطقة واحدة التي أعتقد انها مثيرة للاهتمام،
which many of you may have now that we've thrown
التي الكثير منكم ربما قد تعرفون
microbes into the crowd, is something that I would call "germophobia."
أننا رمينا ميكروبات في الجمع، هو شيء قد أسميه "جرموفوبيا."
So people are really into cleanliness, right?
لذا فإن الناس مقبلين على النظافة، صحيح؟
We have antibiotics in our kitchen counters,
لدينا مضادات حيوية في منضدة المطبخ،
people are washing every part of them all of the time,
الناس يغسلون كل جزء منهم في كل الوقت،
we pump antibiotics into our food, into our communities,
نضخ المضادات الحيوية إلى طعامنا، ومجتمعاتنا،
we take antibiotics excessively.
نستخدم المضادات بإفراط.
And killing pathogens is a good thing if you're sick,
وقتل مسببات المرض شيء جيد إذا كنت مريض،
but we should understand that when we pump chemicals
لكن يجب أن نفهم أنه عندما نضخ الكيماويات
and antibiotics into our world, that we're also killing
و المضادات إلى عالمنا، أننا نقتل أيضاً
the cloud of microbes that live in and on us.
سحابة الميكروبات التي تعيش علينا وداحلنا.
And excessive use of antibiotics, in particular in children,
و الإستخدام المفرط للمضادات الحيوية، بالتحديد في الأطفال،
has been shown to be associated with, again, risk factors
أثبت مرة أخرى، عناصر خطر
for obesity, for autoimmune diseases, for a variety
للسمنة، أمراض المناعة الذاتية، للعديد
of problems that are probably due to disruption
من المشاكل التي قد تكون بسبب الإخلال
of the microbial community.
بالمجتمع الميكروبي.
So the microbial community can go wrong
لذا المجتمع الميكروبي قد يخطئ
whether we want it to or not,
سواءً أردنا ذلك أم لم نرده،
or we can kill it with antibiotics,
أو يمكن ان نقتله بالمضادات الحيوية،
but what can we do to restore it?
لكن ماذا نستطيع أن نفعل لإستعادته؟
I'm sure many people here have heard about probiotics.
أنا متأكد أن العديد من الأشخاص هنا قد سمع عن البروبيوتيك.
Probiotics are one thing that you can try and do to restore
البروبيوتيك شيء واحد تستطيع أن تجربه لإستعادة
the microbial community that is in and on you.
المجتمع الميكروبي داخلك وعليك.
And they definitely have been shown to be effective in some cases.
و هي بالتأكيد قد أثبتت فعاليتها في بعض الحالات.
There's a project going on at UC Davis where people are using
يوجد مشروع يجرى في UC Davis حيث يستخدم الناس
probiotics to try and treat, prevent,
البروبيوتك لمحاولة علاج، منع،
necrotizing enterocolitis in premature infants.
التهاب الأمعاء في الخدج.
Premature infants have real problems with their microbial community.
الخدج يواجهون مشاكل حقيقية في مجتمعهم الميكروبي.
And it may be that probiotics can help prevent
وقد تساعد البروبيوتيك في منع
the development of this horrible necrotizing enterocolitis
تطور هذا الالتهاب الناخر للأمعاء
in these premature infants.
في هؤلاء الخدج.
But probiotics are sort of a very, very simple solution.
لكن البروبيوتيك هي تقريباً حل نوعاً ما جداً جداً بسيط.
Most of the pills that you can take or the yogurts that you can eat
معظم الحبوب التي تأخذها أو الروب الذي تستطيع تناوله
have one or two species in them, maybe five species in them,
فيه فصيلة أو فصيلتين، ربما خمس
and the human community is thousands upon thousands of species.
والمجتمع البشري مكون من آلاف فوق آلاف من الفصائل
So what can we do to restore our microbial community
لذا ماذا نستطيع أن نفعل لاسترجاع مجتمعنا الميكروبي
when we have thousands and thousands of species on us?
عندما نكون نملك آلاف الآلاف علينا؟
Well, one thing that animals seem to do is,
حسناً، شيئاً ما واحد يبدو أن الحيوانات تفعله،
they eat poo -- coprophagia.
يأكلون البراز -- أكل البراز.
And it turns out that many veterinarians,
واتضح أن العديد من البيطرين،
old school veterinarians in particular,
البيطرين من المدرسة القديمة بالتحديد،
have been doing something called "poo tea,"
كانوا يفعلون شيئاً ما يسمى ب "fبو تي"
not booty, but poo tea, to treat colic and other
ليس بوتي، لكن شاي البراز، لمعالجة المغص و أمراض أخرى
ailments in horses and cows and things like that,
في الأحصنة والبقر و أشياء مثل ذلك،
where you make tea from the poo from a healthy
حيث تصنع شاي من براز حيوان بصحة جيدة
individual animal and you feed it to a sick animal.
وتطعمه لحيوان مريض.
Although, unless you have a fistulated cow with a big hole in its side,
بالرغم، مالم يكن لديك بقرة لديها ناسور
and you can put your hand into its rumen,
وتستطيع أن تضع يدك على أمعاءها،
it's hard to imagine that the delivery of microbes
يصعب تخيل وصول الميكروبات مباشرة من أفواهنا
directly into the mouth and through the entire
إلى كامل الجهاز الهضمي
top of the digestive tract is the best delivery system,
هو أفضل نظام وموصل،
so you may have heard in people they are now doing
لذا ربما كنتم قد سمعتم عن أشخاص الآن يقومون
fecal transplants, where rather than delivering
بزراعة البراز، حيث بدلاً من ايصال
a couple of probiotic microbes through the mouth,
بضع من ميكروبات البروبيوتك من خلال الفم،
they are delivering a community of probiotics,
فهم يوصلون مجتمع من البروبيوتيك
a community of microbes from a healthy donor,
مجتمع من الميكروبات من متبرع بصحة جيدة،
through the other end.
خلال النهاية الأخرى.
And this has turned out to be very effective in fighting
و اتضح أن هذه الطريقة فعالة في محاربة
certain intransigent infectious diseases
أنواع محددة عنيدة من الأمراض المعدية
like Clostridium difficile infections that can stay
مثل المطثية العسيرة التي قد تبقى
with people for years and years and years.
مع الأشخاص لسنين وسنين وسنين.
Transplants of the feces, of the microbes from the feces,
.زراعة الفضلات، الميكروبات من الفضلات،
from a healthy donor has actually been shown to cure
من متبرع صحي أظهرت العلاج
systemic C. dif infections in some people.
النظام سي.و بعض الإلتهابات الصعبة في بعض الأشخاص.
Now what these transplants, these fecal transplants, or
الآن ما هي هذه الزراعات، هذه الزراعات للفضلات أو
the poo tea suggest to me, and many other people
شاي البراز يقترح علي، والعديد من الأشخاص
have come up with this same idea, is that
اتوا بهذه الفكرة، وهي
the microbial community in and on us, it's an organ.
المجتمع الميكروبي الذي يعيش بداخلنا وعلينا.
We should view it as a functioning organ, part of ourselves.
يجب أن ننظر إليه كعضو فعال، جزء من أنفسنا.
We should treat it carefully and with respect,
يجب أن نتعامل معه بحذر و احترام،
and we do not want to mess with it, say by C-sections
ولا نريد أن نتلاعب به، فلنفرض العمليات القيصرية
or by antibiotics or excessive cleanliness,
أو المضادت الحيوي أو النظافة الزائدة،
without some real good justification.
بدون سبب حقيقي.
And what the DNA sequencing technologies are allowing people to do now
و ماهي تقنيات متسلسلات الدي إن أي التي تسمح للناس
is do detailed studies of, say, 100 patients who have Crohn's disease
أن يعملوا دراسات مفصلة، لنفرض 100مريض يعانون من مرض كرون
and 100 people who don't have Crohn's disease.
و 100 مريض لا يعانون منه.
Or 100 people who took antibiotics when they were little,
أو 100 شخص أخذوا مضادات حيوية عندما كانوا صغاراً،
and 100 people who did not take antibiotics.
و 100 آخرون لم يأخذوها.
And we can now start to compare the community of microbes
و يمكننا أن نبدأ الآن بمقارنة المجتمعات الميكروبية
and their genes and see if there are differences.
و جيناتهم و نعرف إذا كان هناك فروقات.
And eventually we may be able to understand if they're not
و في النهاية ربما قد نكون استطعنا أن نفهم إذا كانت
just correlative differences, but causative.
فروقات متلازمة، لكن مسببة.
Studies in model systems like mouse and other animals
الدراسات في أنظمة نماذج مثل الفأر و حيونات أخرى
are also helping do this, but people are now using
هي أيضاً تساعدنا في عمل هذا، لكن الناس الآن يستخدمون
these technologies because they've gotten very cheap,
هذه التقنيات لأنها أصبحت جداً رخيصة،
to study the microbes in and on a variety of people.
لدراسة الميكروبات في وعلى عينات منوعة من الناس
So, in wrapping up, what I want to tell you about is,
لذا، لتلخيص الموضوع، ما أريد أن أخبركم عنه هو،
I didn't tell you a part of the story of coming down with diabetes.
أني لم أخبركم جزء من قصة العودة من مرض السكري.
It turns out that my father was an M.D.,
اتضح أن والدي طبيب مختص
actually studied hormones. I told him many times
وفي الحقيقة كان يدرس الهرمونات. أخبرته عدة مرات
that I was tired, thirsty, not feeling very good.
أني تعب، عطش، لا أشعر بشعور جيد.
And he shrugged it off, I think he either thought
وتجاهل ذلك، أعتقد أنه إما
I was just complaining a lot, or it was the typical
أني كنت أتشكى كثيراً، أو أنها كانت
M.D. "nothing can be wrong with my children."
الإعتقاد المثالية للأطباء "لا شيء قد يصيب أطفالي"
We even went to the International Society of Endocrinology
حتى أننا ذهبنا المجتمع العام للغدد الصماء
meeting as family in Quebec.
لنلتقي كعائلة في كيبيك.
And I was getting up every five minutes to pee,
وكنت أقوم كل خمس دقائق للتبول،
and drinking everybody's water at the table,
و أشرب ماء الجميع على الطاولة،
and I think they all thought I was a druggie.
و اعتقد أن الجميع اعتقد أني مدمن مخدرات.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But the reason I'm telling you this is that
لكن سبب إخباري إياكم ماسبق أن
the medical community, my father as an example,
المجتمع الطبي، والدي كمثالـ
sometimes doesn't see what's right in front of their eyes.
أحياناً لا يرون ماهو أمام أعينهم.
The microbial cloud, it is right in front of us.
السحابة الميكروبية، إنها أمامنا مباشرة.
We can't see it most of the time. It's invisible.
لا نستطيع رؤيتها معظم الوقت.
They're microbes. They're tiny.
إنها ميكروبات. صغيرة.
But we can see them through their DNA,
لكن نستطيع رؤيتها من خلال الدي إن أي الخاص بها،
we can see them through the effects that they have on people.
نستطيع رؤيتها من خلال الآثار التي تحدث للناس.
And what we need now
وما نحتاج الآن
is to start thinking about this microbial community in the context
هو أن نبدأ بالتفكير في هذه المجتمعات الميكروبية في سياق
of everything in human medicine.
دراسة كل شيء في الطب البشري.
It doesn't mean that it affects every part of us,
لا يعني أنها تؤثر على كل جزء منا،
but it might.
لكنها قد تؤثر.
What we need is a full field guide to the microbes
ما نحتاجه هو دليل حقل كامل للميكروبات
that live in and on people, so that we can understand
التي تعيش على الناس وداخلهم، حتى نستطيع فهم
what they're doing to our lives.
ماتفعل في حياتنا.
We are them. They are us.
نحن هم. هم نحن.
Thank you.
شكراً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)